Guide to the Basil Lee Whitener Papers, 1889-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence (Legislative) Series, 1956-1968
  - 85th Congress, 1st and 2nd Sessions, 1957-1958
    - Smathers Bill (S. 3778); Social Security; Soil Bank Program; Strackbein, O. R. (The Nation-Wide Committee on Import-Export Policy); Stroupe, Mrs. C. B., Jr. (Box 83, Folder 1-6)
    - T (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Tariff; Television, Pay; Textile Imports (Wool) (Box 83, Folder 8-10)
    - U - V (Box 83, Folder 11-12)
    - W (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Patterson, Jessie L. McCourtie; Wilkins, W. Y., Jr. (Box 84, Folder 2-3)
    - X - Z (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - 86th Congress, 1st Session, 1959
    - A - C (Box 85, Folder 1-5)
    - Cotton (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - D - F (Box 85, Folder 7-9)
    - Foreign Aid-Rutherford County; Foreign Aid-Shelby, N.C. (Box 86, Folder 1-5)
    - G (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - H - L (Box 87, Folder 1-5)
    - Labor Reform Legislation (Box 87, Folder 6-8)
    - Labor Reform Legislation (Box 88, Folder 1-4)
    - Mc, N - P (Box 88, Folder 5-8)
    - R - S (Box 89, Folder 1-2)
    - Senate Labor Bill (S. 1555) (Box 89, Folder 3-4)
    - T. U. W - Z (Box 89, Folder 5-8)
  - 86th Congress, 2nd Session, 1960
    - A (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Asheville Air Service (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - B - C (Box 90, Folder 3-6)
    - Catholic Dictionary; Civil War Centennial; Clarkson, Francis; Cotton (Box 90, Folder 7-10)
    - D - E (Box 90, Folder 11-12)
    - F - O (Box 91, Folder 1-11)
    - P - Z (Box 92, Folder 1-10)
  - 87th Congress, 1st Session, 1961
    - A - F (Box 93, Folder 1-8)
    - Far East Trip (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - G (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - H - M (Box 94, Folder 1-8)
    - Minimum Wage (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - N (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - O - R (Box 95, Folder 1-4)
    - Rules Committee (Box 95, Folder 5-6)
    - S (Box 95, Folder 7-8)
    - T (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Truck Tax (Box 96, Folder 2-4)
    - U - Z (Box 96, Folder 5-9)
  - 87th Congress, 2nd Session,1962
    - A - C (Box 97, Folder 1-4)
    - College Academic Facilities Act of1962(H.R. 8900) (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - D - F (Box 97, Folder 6-8)
    - Food and Agricultural Act of1962(H.R. 11222) (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - G - Mc (Box 98, Folder 2-9)
    - M (Box 99, Folder 1-2)
    - Medical Care Legislation (Box 99, Folder 3-5)
    - Minimum Freight Rate Bills (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - N - R (Box 100, Folder 2-6)
    - Revenue Act of1962(H.R. 10650) (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - S - U (Box 101, Folder 1-4)
    - Unemployment Compensation Amendments Bill (H.R. 7640) (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - V - Z (Box 101, Folder 6-8)
  - 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963
    - A - E (Box 102, Folder 1-7)
    - F - O (Box 103, Folder 1-12)
    - P - Z (Box 104, Folder 1-10)
  - 88th Congress, 2nd Session, 1964
    - A - C (Box 105, Folder 1-5)
    - Civil Rights Bill (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - D - G (Box 105, Folder 7-10)
    - H - O (Box 106, Folder 1-11)
    - P (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Prayer (Box 107, Folder 2-6)
    - Q - Z (Box 108, Folder 1-8)
  - 89th Congress, 1st Session,1965
    - A - E (Box 109, Folder 1-7)
    - Eldercare, Herlong-Curtis Bill (H.R. 3727) (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - F - J (Box 110, Folder 2-7)
  - 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965
    - K - N. P - R (Box 111, Folder 1-10)
    - S - T (Box 112, Folder 1-3)
    - Taft-Hartley Act (1965, Jan. 12 - June 7) (Box 112, Folder 4-6)
    - Taft-Hartley Act (1965, June 8 - July 26) (Box 113, Folder 1-2)
    - U - Z (Box 113, Folder 3-5)
  - 89th Congress, 2nd Session, 1966
    - A - D (Box 114, Folder 1-6)
    - E - J (Box 115, Folder 1-8)
    - K - P (Box 116, Folder 1-8)
    - Q - Z (Box 117, Folder 1-9)
  - 90th Congress, 1st Session, 1967
    - A - E (Box 118, Folder 1-7)
    - F - J (Box 119, Folder 1-7)
    - K - L (Box 120, Folder 1-3)
    - Legislation,1967 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - M - O (Box 120, Folder 5-9)
    - P (Box 121, Folder 1-2)
    - Powell, Adam Clayton (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Q - S (1967, Jan. - Apr.) (Box 121, Folder 4-7)
    - S (1967, May- Dec.) - Z (Box 122, Folder 1-8)
  - 90th Congress, 2nd Session, 1968
    - A - E (Box 123, Folder 1-7)
    - F - J (Box 124, Folder 1-6)
    - Johnson, Lyndon Baines (State of the Union Message) (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - K - L (Box 124, Folder 8-9)
    - Mc - R (Box 125, Folder 1-9)
    - S - T (Box 126, Folder 1-4)
    - Textiles and Apparel (Box 127, Folder 1-2)
    - U - Z (Box 127, Folder 3-7)
    - Includes printed material, such as Status of Major Bills - First Session, Extension of Remarks of Whitener on October 13, 1966from the Congressional Record and information on appropriations bills. ' (Box 307, Folder 1)
- District of Columbia Series, 1961-1968
  Contains correspondence and other papers about matters in the District of Columbia. This important series reflects Whitener's work as a member of the House Committee on the District of Columbia, 1961-1968, as well as a member of certain subcommittees. See the page in this inventory which describes his committee assignments for further information concerning his specific subcommittee assignments. The two major files in this series are Legislative Bills and Subject Files for Legislation, etc.
  - Legislative Bills
    Included are bills, primarily introduced by Whitener, which concern such issues in the District of Columbia as police, courts, crime, traffic, schools, etc. Sometimes only a draft or copy of the bill is enclosed, but other folders additionally contain reports and supplemental information. The papers, which are arranged by Congress and session, and by specific bill (H.R.) number, run from the 88th Congress, First Session, 1963, to the 90th Congress, Second Session, 1968. A comprehensive listing of the title and number of each bill in this category is filed in folder one of the first box of the Legislative Bills Files. Some subject entries have been made for important content, such as crime, but not for most bill names.
    - 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963 (Box 128, Folder 2-11)
    - 88th Congress, 2nd Session, 1964 (Box 128, Folder 12)
    - 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965 (Box 128, Folder 13-19)
    - 89th Congress, 2nd Session, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 1-6)
    - 90th Congress, 1st Session, 1967 (Box 129, Folder 7-13)
    - 90th Congress, 2nd Session, 1968 (Box 129, Folder 14-17)
  - Subject Files for Legislation, Etc.
    There are three major areas covered in this file:
    I. District Committee
    II. District of Columbia. Including material about fiscal affairs, highways, home rule, housing, schools, etc. in the District of Columbia.
    III. Rapid Transit
    Concerns legislative proposals for a rapid transit system in Washington, D. C., and surrounding areas. Related folders included are the National Capital Transportation Act, Transit Program for the National Capital Region, and Japanese Railways. Whitener was chairman of Subcommittee VI on Rapid Transit.
    - District Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 129, Folder 18-20)
    - District Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 130, Folder 1-6)
    - District Committee,1966and undated (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - District Committee:
      - Special Subcommittee on Traffic, Streets, and Highways, 1962, May - Oct.and undated (Box 131, Folder 2-3)
      - Subcommittee on Rapid Transit, 1963, June - Dec.and undated (Box 131, Folder 4-5)
    - District of Columbia:
      - Certified Public Accountants, 1963-1965 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - Fiscal Affairs, 1962-1965and undated (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Highways, 1964-1965 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - Home Rule, 1962-1965 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      - Housing, 1963-1965and undated (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - Schools, 1963-1965and undated (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - District Revenue Bill, 1963and undated (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Glover-Archbold Parkway Bill (S. 2436), 1962and undated (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Japanese National Railways, 1963-1964 (Box 133, Folder 3-4)
    - National Capital Transportation Act of1965(H.R. 4822), 1965, Jan. - June (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Rapid Transit, 1963-1965,June (Box 134, Folder 2-5)
      Folders contain information relative to proposals for a rapid transit system in Washington, D. C., and surrounding areas.
    - Rapid Transit, 1965, Julyand undated (Box 135, Folder 1-2)
    - Transit Program for the National Capital Region (H.R. 8929), 1963and undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Miscellany, 1960-1965and undated (Box 135, Folder 4-5)
- Judiciary Series, 1950-1966,primarily 1957-1966
  This series concerns legislation and other material loosely related to the work of the House Committee on the Judiciary. Whitener was a member of the Judiciary Committee from 1959 to 1968. See the page earlier in this inventory which describes his committee assignments for further information concerning his specific subcommittee assignments. The Judiciary Series and Judiciary Committee Series have been kept separate because they were organized this way in Whitener's office. The Judiciary Committee Series contains folders for the work of this committee and certain sub-committees. The Judiciary Series is larger and more general in nature. The two major files in this series are Legislative Bills, the largest section, and Subject Files for Legislation, etc.
  - Legislative Bills
    In this section, which forms a major part of the Judiciary Series, are numerous folders for various House of Representatives bills, as well as for a few House Joint Resolutions, House Concurrent Resolutions, and Senate Bills. Whitener introduced about two-thirds of the bills represented in this section. The folders usually contain a copy of the bill, and often printed reports, correspondence, and other background information. There was no apparent order to the bills. Therefore, they were arranged by Congress and session, and by specific bill (H.R.) number, and run from the 85th Congress, 1st Session, 1957 to the 89th Congress, 2nd session, 1966. A comprehensive listing of the title and number of each bill in this category is filed in folder one of the first box of the Legislative Bills files. Some subject entries have been made for important content, such as civil rights, but not for most bill names.
    - 85th Congress, 1st Session, 1957 (Box 136, Folder 1A-8)
    - 85th Congress, 2nd Session, 1958 (Box 136, Folder 9-14)
    - 86th Congress, 1st Session, 1959:
      - H.J. Res. 134 - H.R. 2238 (Box 136, Folder 15-23)
      - H.R. 2239 - H.R. 5921 (Box 137, Folder 1-27)
      - H.R. 6159 - H.R. 8715 (Box 138, Folder 1-7)
    - 86th Congress, 2nd Session, 1960 (Box 138, Folder 8-13)
    - 87th Congress, 1st Session, 1961:
      - H. Con. Res. 77 - H.R. 3692 (Box 138, Folder 14-22)
      - H.R. 4472 - S. 167 (Box 139, Folder 1-8)
    - 87th Congress, 2nd Session, 1962 (Box 139, Folder 9-14)
    - 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963:
      - H.J. Res. 714 (Box 139, Folder 15-16)
      - H.R. 3439 - H.R. 7152 (Box 140, Folder 1-11)
    - 88th Congress, 2nd Session, 1964:
      - H.R. 10380 - H.R. 11377 (Box 140, Folder 12-15)
      - H.R. 11809 - H.R. 11927 (Box 141, Folder 1-2)
    - 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965 (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - 89th Congress, 2nd Session, 1966 (Box 141, Folder 4-6)
    - Bills introduced by Whitener during the 85th Congress, 1st Session, 1957,through the 87th Congress, 2nd Session, 1962 (Box 141, Folder 7)
  - Subject Files for Legislation, Etc.
    Included are three boxes of material on such topics as civil rights, the courts, and the trial in 1964 of James R. Hoffa. The subjects are in an alphabetical arrangement.
    - Civil Rights, 1950-1956 (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Civil Rights, 1957-1959 (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Civil Rights, 1960-1963 (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Civil Rights, undated (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Courts, 1957 (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Courts, 1958, 1960 (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Debate File, 1959-1960 (Box 143, Folder 1)
      Miscellaneous information gathered by Whitener concerning court cases, elections, voting, etc.
    - Habeas Corpus, 1955-1959 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Hoffa, 1964, Feb. (Box 143, Folder 3)
      Four folders concerning the U.S. vs. Hoffa trial in 1964 conducted in the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Tennessee, Southern Division, in Chattanooga. Included is some correspondence, and copies of letters to Emanuel Celler, Chairman of the House Committee on the Judiciary; many affidavits; and other material relating to the court case.
    - Hoffa, 1964, Mar. (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Hoffa, 1964, Apr.-Aug. (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Hoffa, 1963-1964 and undated (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Interstate Commerce Taxation, 1959 (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Judgeships, N.C., 1958, Feb. - 1961, Feb. (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - Judgeships, N.C., 1961, Mar. - Aug. and undated (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - National Service Life Insurance, 1961-1965 (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Port of New York Authority, 1960 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Prayer in Public Schools, 1961-1962 (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Reapportionment of State Legislatures, 1963-1964 (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - The Star-Spangled Banner, 1954-1961 (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1963 (Box 144, Folder 7)
      Concerns charges against Yarmolinsky, special assistant to Defense Secretary Robert McNamara. The basic charge was that he admitted to World War II Army security investigators that he had attended meetings of theYoung Communist League.
- Judiciary Committee Series, 1961-1968
  In this series are papers which primarily concern Whitener's duties as a member of the House Committee on the Judiciary. He was a member of this committee from 1959 to 1968. See the page in this inventory which describes his committee assignments for further information concerning his specific subcommittee assignments. Some files relating specifically to the work of the Judiciary Committee, and the subcommittee on which he served, are contained in this series. The Judiciary Committee Series and Judiciary Series have been kept separate because they were organized this way in Whitener's office. The Judiciary Series is larger and more general in nature than this series. The two major files in this series are Legislative Bills and Subject Files for Legislation, Etc.
  - Legislative Bills
    Folders for several House of Representatives bills as well as House Joint Resolution 714, to allow Bible reading and prayer in the public schools, are included in this section. Whitener sponsored many of these bills. The folders usually contain a copy of the bill, and often printed reports, correspondence, and other background information. There was no apparent order to the bills, which fall in the 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963; 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965; and 90th Congress, 1st Session, 1967. Therefore the bills were arranged by Congress and session and by specific bill (H.R.) number. A comprehensive listing of the title and number of each bill in this category is filed in folder one of the first box of the Legislative Bills files. Some Subject entries have been made for important content but not for most bill names.
    - 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963 (Box 145, Folder 2-9)
    - 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965:
      - H.R. 5505 - H.R. 6400 (1965, Mar.) (Box 145A, Folder 1-2 and vol.)
      - H.R. 6400 (1965, Apr. - Juneand undated) (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
    - 90th Congress, 1st Session, 1967
      - H.R. 2158 (Box 146, Folder 3-6)
      - H.R. 2160 - H.R. 2516 (Box 147, Folder 1-3)
  - Subject Files for Legislation, Etc.
    This section contains folders for the Judiciary Committee and Whitener's subcommittee assignments, especially for the Special Subcommittee on State Taxation of Interstate Commerce which covers several folders. A small amount of material pertains to Subcommittee IV. Other important topics are civil rights, East-West trade, and textiles. The subjects are in an alphabetical arrangement.
    - Becker Amendment, 1964 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - Civil Rights, 1966, July (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Civil Rights, 1966., Jul.-1967 and undated (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - East-West Trade, 1961, 1965-1966 (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - East-West Trade, 1967, Jan.- June (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - East-West Trade, 1967, July -Sept. (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - East-West Trade, 1967, Oct.-1968, Mar. (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - East-West Trade, undated (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Integration of Mississippi Schools, 1967 and undated (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Judiciary Committee, 1961-1965 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Judiciary Committee, 1967, Mar.-1968, Apr. (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Judiciary Committee, 1968, May-July and undated (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Judiciary Committee, Special Subcommittee on State Taxation of Interstate Commerce, 1961 (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Judiciary Committee, Special Subcommittee on State Taxation of Interstate Commerce, 1962, Jan.-June (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Judiciary Committee, Special Subcommittee on State Taxation of Interstate Commerce, 1962, July-1963, July (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Judiciary Committee, Special Subcommittee on State Taxation of Interstate Commerce, 1964-1965 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee 4, 1962-1965 (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Jury Selection, 1966 (Box 150, Folder 4)
      Primarily copies of letters of Senator Sam J. Ervin, Jr., who was Chairman of the Senate Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights, concerning jury selection procedures.
    - Textiles, 1966, Aug.-1967, May (Box 150, Folder 5)
      Concerns U.S. textile imports and trade.
    - Textiles, 1967, June-Sept. and undated (Box 150, Folder 6)
- Speeches Series, 1954-1968,primarily 1957-1968
  Includes, in addition to the text of many of Whitener's speeches, remarks of Whitener in Congress, as printed in the Congressional Record. Other unorganized material has been divided into two additional categories: Correspondence; and speech material, printed material, and miscellany.
  - Speeches
    Contains the text of Whitener's speeches, usually in a typed format, but there are some rough drafts and outlines of talks. Whitener delivered these speeches at such functions as post office dedications, meetings of organizations such as the North Carolina Association of Letter Carriers, family reunions, and church services and meetings. Many duplicates were discarded from this section.
    - Speeches, 1955-1962 (Box 151, Folder 1-7)
    - Speeches, 1963-1966 (Box 152, Folder 1-6)
    - Speeches, 1967-1968and undated (Box 153, Folder 1-6)
    - Remarks of Whitener in Congress (Box 153)
      Primarily clippings from the Congressional Record - House of remarks by Whitener. The folders are organized by Congress and session.
    - 85th Congress, 1st Session, 1957- 88th Congress, 2nd Session,1964 (Box 154, Folder 1-8)
    - 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965- 90th Congress, 2nd Session,1968 (Box 155, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence
    - Papers, 1960-1968 (Box 156, Folder 1-2)
  - Speech Material, Printed Material, and Miscellany
    Includes a wide variety of typed, mimeographed, and printed material, such as newsletters and other publications, reports by various private organizations and state and federal agencies, newspaper clippings, news releases, editorial reprints, and campaign material. There are some remarks in the Congressional Record by persons other than Whitener. Much of this section seems to consist of background material for Whitener's speeches.
    - Speech material, 1954-1961 (Box 156, Folder 3-4)
    - Speech material, 1962-1968 (Box 157, Folder 1-4)
- Subject Series, 1953-1968,primarily 1961-1968
  These files were in rough alphabetical order so this arrangement was retained with some minor refinements of folder titles and order. Some Items such as routine individual social security claims, visa applications, routine correspondence, and duplicates were discarded.
  - Agriculture Census, 1964 (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture Department Trip, 1963and undated (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - American Corn Millers Federation, 1965-1966and undated (Box 158, Folder 3)
  - Appalachian Corridor Highway, 1965and undated (Box 158, Folder 4)
  - Avery County Airport, 1961-1964and undated (Box 158, Folder 5)
  - Ball, George, 1963 (Box 158, Folder 6)
  - Beech Mountain Development Corporation, 1963and undated (Box 158, Folder 7)
  - Belmont Abbey College, 1953-1965and undated (Box 158, Folder 8-9)
  - Blue Ridge Parkway Fees, 1963-1968and undated (Box 158, Folder 10)
  - Broad River, 1964 (Box 158, Folder 11)
  - Calendars, 1968 (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - Celatron, Inc., 1963 (Box 159, Folder 2)
  - Census, 1965-1966and undated (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - Census. Gaston County, 1965-1966and undated (Box 159, Folder 4)
  - Cherry Blossom Festival, 1965 (Box 159, Folder 5)
  - Civil Rights, 1965-1966 (Box 159, Folder 6)
  - Copper, 1959; 1966 (Box 159, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Committee Material
    - 1962-1967 (Box 159, Folder 8-10)
    - 1968 and undated (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Democratic Executive Committee (N.C.), 1963-1967and undated (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1964 (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - Duke Power Company, 1962-1968and undated (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Economic Opportunity, 1964and undated (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - Elementary and Secondary Education Act, 1967and undated (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - Federal City Council, 1965 (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - Federal Communications Commission, 1964and undated (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Aid, 1963-1964 (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - Gardner-Webb College, 1964-1965and undated (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Gaston Electrical Contractors, 1964-1965and undated (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Gelormini, Yvette Dosia Angele, 1961-1963and undated (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Guillermo, 1963-1965and undated (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Hickory, North Carolina, 1966-1967 (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1961-1964and undated (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - Immigration, 1965-1966 (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., Messages, 1965-1966 (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., Correspondence,1964Concerning Photographs of Johnson (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Kennedy, John F., Photograph, undated (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Rings Mountain 185th Anniversary,1965 (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Labor Department, 1962-1963and undated (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Medicare, 1965-1966 (Box 161, Folder 13)
  - Middle East, 1967 (Box 161, Folder 14)
  - Morrison, Ethel Hudson, 1961-1965 (Box 161, Folder 15)
  - National Guard (Spindale and Forest City Consolidation),1959 (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1966and undated (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Oteen Veterans Administration Hospital, 1967and undated (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Pfeiffer College, 1966and undated (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Poverty Bills, 1964-1965and undated (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Public Works and Economic Development Act, 1966 (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - Rhododendron Festival, 1963 (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Small Business Administration
    - Papers, 1961-1962 (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Papers, 1963-1965and undated (Box 163, Folder 1-2)
  - Smith, Young, Jr., 1965 (Box 163, Folder 3)
  - Social Security, 1965-1966 (Box 163, Folder 4)
  - Southern Railway, 1966and undated (Box 163, Folder 5)
  - Spruce Pine, North Carolina, 1963-1966and undated (Box 163, Folder 6)
  - State Department. General Information, 1962-1966and undated (Box 163, Folder 7)
  - State Department. Passport Office, 1963-1964 (Box 163, Folder 8)
  - Talon, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Tax Information, 1963-1964Primarily concerns reduction of federal taxes. (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - Tobacco, 1961-1967and undated (Box 164, Folder 3-4)
  - U.S. Cabinet Officers, 1963 (Box 164, Folder 5)
  - Veterans, 1963 (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - Veterans Readjustment Benefits Act, 1966 (Box 164, Folder 7)
  - WAMY Community Action, Inc., 1967and undated (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - Walnut Exports, 1961-1965 (Box 165, Folder 2)